Ryan Daniel Evans

Akron, OH 44319 • (330) 671 1076 • rdevans87@gmail.com

Technical Customer Support Specialist

Summary:

Multifaceted customer service specialist with proficient understanding of technical troubleshooting and valuable experience supporting a variety of software products and services on the web. Self-motivated team player with a strong work ethic and desire to learn new skills.

Core Skills:

- Software Sales (Final Draft)
- Technical Support (CRM, Salesforce)
- Customer Service (CRM, Helpdesk)
- Product Implementation (SAAS)
- QA Testing (Jira, Agile/Scrum)
- Web Design (HTML, CSS)

Employment:

IMDb.com, subsidiary of Amazon.com Customer Service Specialist

08/2019 - Present

Acted quickly to diagnose and troubleshoot technical issues for IMDb's website and mobile apps using CRM tools and resources.

- Collaborated with development team to file bug reports, track unresolved tickets, and manage customer relationships.
- Built fast and effective working relationships with team members of varying seniority, backgrounds and experience.
- Demonstrated ability to solve challenging technical issues and make data-driven decisions to improve customer satisfaction.

Cast & Crew Entertainment Services, LLC. Sr. Product Technical Support Analyst

04/2018 - 08/2019

Assisted with product implementation, software QA testing, and technical support for digital payroll products and services: Studio+, Start+ (SAAS)

- Provided on-site/remote product demonstrations and training sessions to end-users.
- Tracked bug reports, enhancement requests, and software updates using Agile project management Scrum in Jira.
- Acted as liaison between senior leadership to communicate software updates and releases to customer support team.
- Collaborated with product manager and engineering team on development of implementation and end-user training.

Final Draft, Inc., subsidiary of Cast & Crew Entertainment, LLC. 04/2016 – 04/2018 Sales Associate

Responded to a high volume of incoming customer inquiries via phone, email, and live chat to drive sales and provide an excellent customer experience.

- Used Salesforce (CRM) to manage interactions with existing customers and identify new opportunities to increase sales.
- Assisted with QA testing and software launch of two product releases: Final Draft 10 (2016)
 Final Draft 11 (2018).
- Performed in depth product demonstrations and sales presentations for industry professionals at screenwriting conferences and promotional events.

Unified Pictures 03/2015 – 04/2016

Production Executive

Facilitated the relationship between financiers and executive producers on upcoming film projects.

- Communicated effectively under pressure during long periods of high call volumes to provide concise and accurate information to accredited investors.
- Gained valuable understanding of production workflow, budget costs, and private placement memorandums.
- Demonstrated flexibility and persistence to create consistent pipeline of accredited leads for finance department.

Macy's 03/2012 – 03/2015

Sales Supervisor

Managed associates to provide the highest level of customer service through monitoring selling behaviors; taught detailed product knowledge, communicated policies and procedures.

- Consistently exceeded store goals using MAGIC selling best practices to increase customer engagement.
- Ability to analyze daily reports and identify opportunities to increase retail sales within assigned departments.
- Collaborated with merchandising team on upcoming promotional events and changes to department floor plans.
- Directed sales associates to connect with customers in order to build quick rapport and provide an outstanding shopping experience.

Education:

The Ohio State University
Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

University of Central Florida

Bachelor of Arts (B A) Communication and Media Studies

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Communication and Media Studies Completed: August, 2011

Expected: June, 2021